A Guide to the Monticello Music Collection
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Part 5: Monticello Music Collection
  - Fragment of a book of Scotch songs with pianoforte accompaniment. 1 May 1793 (Folder Folder I)
    Pages v-vi of introduction, the table of contents, nos. 1-24 of the lyrics, and nos. 1-23 of the music are intact. Published, Blair-Sweet, Edinburgh. 'The Smiling Morn by Mallet': Air-The Birks of Invermay, 'Here Awa, There Awa' written for this work by Rob.T Burns. English verses to the Same Air written for this work, by Peter Pindar, Esq., 'What Beauties Does Flora Disclose?' by Mr. Crawford, (of the Auchnames Family): Air-Tweedside, 'Beyond Yon Hills by Robert Burns': Air-My Nanie, O. English verses to the same air by Dr. Percy, 'Hear Me, Ye Nymphs,' by Mr. Crawford. Air-The Bush Aboon Traquair, 'One Day I Heard Mary Say,' by Mr. Crawford. Air-I'll Never Leave Thee, 'My Patie is a Lover Gay by Allan Ramsay. Air-Corn Riggs. English Verses to the Same Air [No Author Attributed], Will Ye go to the Ewe-Bughts, Marion? English Verses to the Same Air Written for this Work by Peter Pindar, Esq., 'My Sheep I Neglected by Sir Gilbert Elliot. Air-My Apron Deary, 'Farewell to Lochaber' by Allan Ramsay. English verses to the same air, by William Hamilton, Esq., 'Braw Lads on Yarrow braes, written for this work by Robert Burns. Air-Galla Water. English verses to the same air written for this work by the Hon. Andrew Erskine, Of Kellie, 'Busk Ye, Busk Ye' by William Hamilton, Esp. Air-The Braes of Yarrow. English Verses to the Same Air by the Rev.D Mr. Logan, 'In April, When Come Primroses' by Allan Ramsay. Air-The Yellow Hair'd Laddie, 'Twas in that Season of the Year' by Richard Hewit. Air-Roslin Castle, 'From Thee, Eliza, I Must Go' by Robert Burns. Air-Donald, 'Gin Living Worth' Air-The Waefu' Heart. English verses to the same air, [No Author Attributed], 'There's Auld Rob Morris' written for this work by Robert burns. English verses to the same air [No Author Attributed], 'One Morning Very Early' said to have been written in bedlam by a negro. Air-Gramachree. The following beautiful verses from Duenna, being now frequently attached to this Air are here added although the preceding song is not in the Scotish Dialect, 'O Waly Waly' English verses to the same air by Thomson, 'Ah Chloris, Could I Now But Sit' Air-Gilderoy, 'Oh, Open the Door' as altered by Robert Burns, 'When Wild War's Deadly Blast' written for this work by Robert Burns. Air-The Mill Mill O. English verses to the same air by Allan Ramsay, 'The Night Her Silent Sable Wore' Air-She Rose and Loot Me In, Sweet Annie Frae the Sea-Beach Came. English verses to the same air by Collins, [text only].
  - Six Ariettes Choisis, Avec Accompagnement D'un Clavecin ou Piano Forte Arrange Par Mr. L. (Folder Folder J)
    Prix 4 livre 4 sols A Paris. Chez le Sr. Sieber Musicien rue St. Honore entre la rue D'orlean et Celle des vielles Etuves vis avis l'Hotel D'Aligre chez l'Apothicaire No. 92. Printed sheet music.
    Air de Chimene (Toi qui seul peut lire en mon Coeur...), Air de Didon (Ah! que je fus bien inspiree...), Air de Chimene (Par donnes mon coeur vous offence...), Air de Rodrigue dans Chimene (Tout ce qui dut me rendre heureux tout ce que j'maimais dans la vie...), De l'Acte de Tibule et Delie (Je me prisais l'Amour...), Air de l'Epreuve Villageoise (Bon Dieu com heir a cete fete...), Catalogue de Musique Vocale et Instrumentale appurtenant a Monsieur Sieber.
  - Miscellaneous sheets from Feuilles de Terpsichore ou Journal Compose d'Ouvertures, d'Airs arranges et d'Lirs avec Accompagnement pour le Clavecin. (Folder Folder K)
    Weekly journal published in Paris. Songs with pianoforte accompaniment and solo keyboard works.
    Air de Dardanus (Jour heureux...) 2nd year, No. 17, Airs de Ballet d'Alexandre aux Indes. Solo keyboard. Air d'Oedipe a Colone. Musique de Sacchini. (Votre coeur devint mon azile) 3rd year, No. 19. Air de Dardanus (C'est un charme supreme qui suspendra mon tourment...) No. 44.
  - The Favorite Concerto for the Harpsichord or Pianoforte, Composed by M. Rush. No. 1. (Folder Folder L)
    Price: 2.00. Printed by Longman & Broderip, No. 26 Cheapside, London. Music Sellers to the Royal Family. Title page only.
  - Two printed pages. (Folder Folder M)
    Overture in Thomas & Sally. Possibly keyboard reduction.
  - The Devil Among the Taylor's: A Favorite Air Arranged as a Rondo for the Pianoforte by T. Haigh. (Folder Folder N)
    Printed and sold by Preston at his Wholesale Warehouses, 97 Strand, London. Price: 1.00. Printed sheet music. Pages 1-4.
  - Two unbound pages from a collection entitled Handel's Celebrated Water Music, See the Conquering Hero Comes, and the March in Judas Maccabeus Arranged for the Pianoforte and Harp by P. Rosolli. (Folder Folder O)
    Printed by Goulding D'Almaine, Potter & Company. 20 Soho Square, Westmorland St., Dublin. Price: 2.00, Pianoforte part 1.00. Pages 9, 14-15.
  - Water Parted from the Sea with Variations for the Harpsichord or Pianoforte, also for the German Flute or Violin, by Theodor Smith. (Folder Folder P)
    Printed and Sold by Welcker, No. 9 Hay Market facing the Opera House. Price: 6.00. Printed sheet music. Pages 1-4.